<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></description>
        <link>http://hearingirc.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 20:59:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://hearingirc.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 20:59:51 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2014 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>By the deadline in August 2014 IRC had received 21 outstanding grant proposals
from leading universities around the world in response to the most recent RFP.
While last year’s grant recipients, Steven Colburn (Boston University, USA) &amp;
Theo Goverts (VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam) and Gitte Keidser &amp;
Virginia Best (National Acoustic Laboratories, Australia) were focussing on
research in the field of Perception of dynamic spatial listening scenarios, the
2014 RFP focuses on Neurodegeneration: Perceptual Consequences and
Quantification in Human Subjects.</p>

<p>IRC is very pleased to announce that the 2014 Grant recipients are Prof. John
Grose, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and Dr. Elizabeth Beach,
PhD, National Acoustic Laboratories, Australia.</p>

<p>John Grose is Professor at the department of Otolaryngology - Head &amp; Neck
Surgery, and his work will focus on characterizing auditory neurodegeneration
in humans, combining basic psychoacoustic measurements with
electrophysiological measurements.</p>

<p>“There is increasing evidence that noise exposure can result in permanent
hearing changes even if the ability to detect quiet sounds remains intact”, Dr
John Grose says - “This project looks specifically at whether regular
attendance at loud music venues is associated with a compromised ability to
discern audible sounds over the long term. I am very enthusiastic be working
with the IRC on this project, as we consider this study an important next step
in our understanding of the perceptual consequences of hearing loss and aging”.</p>

<p>The project will be undertaken in the Hearing Research Laboratory at the
University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, which has a distinguished history
of studying human auditory function using both behavioral and
electrophysiological tests.</p>

<p>Elizabeth Beach is a Research Psychologist at NAL, and her work will focus at
addressing outcomes of a potential target group of noise exposed workers, in
combination with basic auditory assessments. Elizabeth says: “It was such a
great topic for the IRC to initiate a request on, and it was a topic that we
had already been thinking about a lot. We&#39;re very much looking forward to the
study and reaching a better understanding of the nature of hidden hearing
loss.&ldquo;</p>

<p>Both projects look at the so-called ‘hidden hearing loss’ being an implication
of degeneration of neurons in the auditory fibers, due to noise exposure. The
term ‘hidden hearing loss’ refers to the fact that it is not obvious from an
audiogram, that hearing has deteriorated (significantly), but speech
understanding in noise is severely reduced.</p>

<p>“Once again we are very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from universities all around the world. We know it takes a big effort to
prepare such applications, and we want to express our thankfulness to all
applicant for their contribution,” said Joel Beilin, 2014-2015 Chair of the
IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2014-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2014-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2014 RFP: Neurodegeneration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>During the last five years, our understanding of the pathophysiology of hearing
loss has been substantially enhanced, and challenged, by the discovery of
auditory neuronal damage, which does not always manifest in the audiogram. This
is a very interesting new area of research, and this year the IRC is requesting
proposals within the topic of Neurodegeneration: Perceptual Consequences and
Quantification in Human Subjects. The $300,000 grant is open to research labs
around the world.</p>

<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">IRC website</a>. The
deadline for proposals is August 15, 2014, and decisions will be announced by
December 31, 2014.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2014-neurodegeneration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2014-neurodegeneration</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2013 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The IRC received 24 outstanding grant proposals from around the world for this
most recent RFP. <a href="/news/announcing-the-first-irc-grant-recipients/">Last May</a>,
Piers Dawes, Ph.D., and Andrea Pittman, Ph.D., were
awarded the first IRC grants for research aimed to advance the understanding of
the interaction between cognition and hearing aids.</p>

<p>Goverts is head of the Audiological Center and a medical physicist audiologist
at the VU University Medical Center in Amsterdam, and Colburn is the director
of the Hearing Research Center and professor of biomedical engineering at
Boston University. Their research will take a detailed look at speech
recognition in realistic dynamic listening scenarios.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We are very excited by the opportunities provided by this grant to address
questions related to spatial hearing in complicated listening situations,” said
Goverts. “We hope that our work will help audiologists to better treat people
with hearing problems.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Best currently works as a research scientist with the National Acoustic
Laboratories in Sydney, Australia, and as a research assistant professor at
Hearing Research Center, Boston University. Her research will examine a dynamic
speech comprehension task for assessing real-world listening ability and
hearing aid benefit.</p>

<p>“We are delighted that the IRC has decided to support this work. The grant will
enable us to develop a new test that measures how well people can follow
dynamic conversations in noisy places,” said Best. “Using this test we will
also gather new knowledge about how hearing loss and hearing aids affect this
critical part of everyday communication.&ldquo;</p>

<p>&quot;We are very pleased to have received quite a large number of excellent
proposals from renowned universities all around the world, and we want to thank
every applicant for his or her contribution,” said Stefan Launer, 2013 Chair of
the IRC. “It shows us that we have selected a topic of great interest and
potential for the research community and thus our entire industry. We have
selected proposals that present a mixture between innovative approaches to
basic science and direct clinical applicability. We wish the two selected
research teams great success with their projects, and we very much look forward
to seeing the results being openly and publicly presented and discussed.
Hopefully this initiative will stimulate further research in this exciting
field.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2013-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2013-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RFP 2013 Perception of dynamic spatial listening scenarios]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dear colleagues,</p>

<p>The hearing aid industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to create
the Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) to develop and direct a
non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the hearing
aid industry, its customers, and end users.</p>

<p>The IRC is requesting proposals for a research project on “Perception of
dynamic spatial listening scenarios”. The $300,000 grant pool is open to
research labs around the world.  Further details are available on the IRC web
site at <a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a> and in attached document.</p>

<p>The IRC board is comprised of the heads of research from the top hearing aid
manufacturers in the world including GN ReSound’s Andrew Dittberner; Oticon’s
Graham Naylor; Phonak’s Stefan Launer; Siemens’ Joel Beilin; Starkey Hearing
Technologies’ Brent Edwards; and Widex’ Lars Sunesen.</p>

<p>The deadline for proposals is September 1, 2013, and decisions will be
announced by December 31, 2013.</p>

<p>I am chairman of IRC for 2013, and enquiries may be directed to me or any of
the others named above.</p>

<p>Please feel free to further distribute this email to researcher you think might
are interested in this field.</p>

<p>Best regards<br>
Stefan Launer</p>

<p>VP Science and Technology<br>
Phonak AG</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2013-perception-of-dynamic-spatial-listening-scenarios</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2013-perception-of-dynamic-spatial-listening-scenarios</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the First IRC Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://hearingirc.com/#about">Hearing Industry Research Consortium</a> (IRC)
is excited to announce the results of its first public Request For grant
Proposals (RFP). Piers Dawes, Ph.D, Research Fellow at the University of
Manchester, and Andrea Pittman, Ph.D., Associate Professor at Arizona State
University, were selected to each receive $150,000 for their research proposals
that are aimed to advance the understanding of the interaction between
cognition and hearing aids.</p>

<p>The IRC received more than fifteen outstanding grant proposals after
<a href="http://hearingirc.com/worldwide-hearing-industry-research-consortium-announced/">announcing</a>
the grant and formation of the consortium last August at the International
Hearing Aid Research Conference in Lake Tahoe, California.</p>

<p>Dawes’ research will focus on “Tuning of auditory attention: the importance for
hearing aid acclimatization and benefit.” “Hearing loss is very common and
leads to difficulties with communication, social isolation, depression, poor
general health and possibly cognitive decline,” said Dawes. “One reason for the
low use of hearing aids is problems adjusting to listening with hearing aids.
We are very excited by our new IRC-funded research because we think this
research will address a key reason why some people struggle to adjust to
hearing aids. The research could have a big impact in improving adjustment to
hearing aids, increasing benefit and improving quality of life.”</p>

<p>Pittman’s research will examine “Assessing advanced hearing aid features using
behavioral tasks that vary in cognitive demand.” “We believe that the formation
of an Industry Research Consortium is a bold and innovative move by the major
hearing aid manufacturers to advance the science and outcomes of hearing
technology,” said Pittman. “We look forward to collaborating with these
companies as we examine the benefits of advanced hearing aid features to the
cognitive demands of children and adults with hearing loss.”</p>

<p>“Our field is just beginning to understand how hearing aids can positively
affect cognition and how cognitive ability affects hearing aid benefit,” said
Stefan Launer, the 2013 chair of the IRC. “We are excited to be able to advance
this important research area through the funding of projects by these two
outstanding researchers at world-class universities.”</p>

<p>The IRC will repeat the funding of new research projects every year, with
different research goals for each RFP. A new RFP for 2013 will be released this
coming summer.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-first-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-first-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worldwide Hearing Industry Research Consortium Announced]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>$300,000 Grant to be Awarded to Winning Proposal on Interaction of Cognition
and Hearing Aids</p>

<p>The hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to create the
Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) to develop and direct a
non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the hearing
aid industry, its customers and end users.</p>

<p>As its first act, the IRC is requesting proposals for a research project on the
interaction of cognition and hearing aids. The $300,000 grant was announced at
the International Hearing Aid Research Conference in Lake Tahoe, Calif., and is
open to research labs around the world.</p>

<p>The IRC board is comprised of the heads of research from the top hearing aid
manufacturers in the world including GN ReSound’s Andrew Dittberner; Oticon’s
Graham Naylor; Phonak’s Stefan Launer; Siemens’ Joel Beilin; Starkey Hearing
Technologies’ Brent Edwards; and Widex’ Lars Sunesen.</p>

<p>Applications are available on the IRC web site at <a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a> . The
deadline for proposals is November 1, 2012, and decisions will be announced by
December 31, 2012.</p>

<p>About the Hearing Industry Research Consortium The Hearing Industry Research
Consortium (IRC) is made up of the heads of research from the top hearing aid
manufactures in the world, which include GN ReSound, Oticon, Phonak, Siemens,
Starkey Hearing Technologies and Widex. The IRC was created to have a
non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the hearing
aid industry, its customers and end users. For more information about the
Hearing Industry Research Consortium, visit <a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/worldwide-hearing-industry-research-consortium-announced</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/worldwide-hearing-industry-research-consortium-announced</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Industry Research Consortium has a new website]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The hearing industry research consortium has a new website to support industry-wide research initiatives.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/industry-research-consortium-has-a-new-website</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/industry-research-consortium-has-a-new-website</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>