<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></description>
        <link>http://hearingirc.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 23:03:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://hearingirc.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 23:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2017 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The IRC received seventeen outstanding proposals from leading universities and
research institutions around the world in response to its 2017 request for
proposals on the impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in
hearing impaired adults. This topic area recognizes the importance of
considering that real-life communication does not occur solely in the auditory
domain, but instead triggers simultaneous activation of different modalities,
requiring cross-modal integration. The IRC is pleased to announce that the grant
recipients are a team lead by Principal Investigator Prof. Hans Colonius, Carl
von Ossietzky Universitat Oldenburg, Germany and another team lead by Prof. Anu
Sharma, University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado, USA.</p>
<p>Hans Colonius is a professor in the Department of Psychology and the Cluster of
Excellence “Hearing4all”, Carl von Ossietzky University Oldenburg. He and his
co-workers, Professor Christiane Thiel, Anja Gieseler, Maike Tahden, and Dr.
Stephanie Rosemann will focus on how hearing aid usage in mild-to-moderately
hearing-impaired elderly affects audiovisual integration, speech perception,
cognitive performance and neural connectivity using both psychophysical methods
and fMRI.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited about being able to follow up on our previous work and to
finally realize the project that we have been thinking about for the last
years”, said Prof. Colonius, “by investigating the causal relations between
audiovisual integration, hearing aid use and speech performance in a
longitudinal study!”</p>
<p>Anu Sharma is a Professor in the Department of Speech Language Hearing Sciences,
Institute of Cognitive Science, and Center for Neuroscience at the University of
Colorado Boulder. Her work will focus on examining changes in cross-modal
neuroplasticity and auditory visual processing in age-related hearing loss and
whether intervention with amplification restores auditory visual integration and
underlying cortical networks to a normal state.</p>
<p>Prof. Sharma said: “This is a timely and much-needed topic that was requested by
the IRC. We are excited about being able to conduct the study which will allow
us to better understand the neuroplastic changes underlying auditory visual
integration in hearing loss and how they are impacted by amplification”.</p>
<p>The IRC is once again very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from leading researchers all around the world. “We know it takes a big effort to
prepare such applications, and we want to express our sincere appreciation to
all applicants for their contribution,” said Sridhar Kalluri, 2017-2018 Chair of
the IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2017-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2017-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2017 RFP: "The impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in hearing impaired adults"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Since 2010 the hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to
sponsor a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefiting the
hearing aid industry, its customers, and end users. The framework for this
collaboration is the <a href="http://hearingirc.com/">Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC)</a>.</p>
<p>This year&#39;s <a href="http://rfp.hearingirc.com">Request for Proposal (RfP)</a> is entitled
&quot;The impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in hearing
impaired adults&quot;. Hearing IRC wishes to support pre-competitive research that
advances understanding of the effects of both hearing aid processing and
individual audiovisual integration abilities on hearing aid benefit in real-life
speech communication. For many years, research on the effects of hearing-aid
use has mainly considered factors related to auditory perception. Real-life
communication, however, does not occur solely in the auditory domain, but
instead triggers simultaneous activation of different modalities, requiring
cross-modal integration.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com/">Hearing IRC web site</a>.
The deadline for proposals is August 18th, 2017, and decisions will be announced
by December 31, 2017.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2017-audiovisual-integration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2017-audiovisual-integration</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2016 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>By the deadline of August 2016 IRC had received a large number of outstanding
grant proposals from leading universities around the world in response to this
year’s request for proposals on auditory ecology and its contribution to quality
of life, with emphasis on the individual.</p>
<p>IRC is very pleased to announce that the 2016 grant recipient is the team lead
by Principal Investigator Dr Inga Holube, Institute of Hearing Technology and
Audiology, Jade University of Applied Sciences in Oldenburg in cooperation with
Dr. Markus Meis from Hörzentrum Oldenburg, Germany.</p>
<p>The project explores the individual hearing aid benefit in real life by
developing tools that momentarily assess the health-related quality of life in
individual every-day listening situations. The concept uniquely combines the
analysis of the acoustical conditions, self-assessments and external
observations that allow characterizing psychologically and sociologically the
behavior of hearing-impaired persons in self-selected environments.</p>
<p>“Once again we are very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from universities all around the world. We know it takes a big effort to prepare
such applications, and we want to express our sincere appreciation s to all
applicants for their contribution,” said Stefan Launer, 2016-2017 Chair of the
IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2016-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2016-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2016 RFP: Auditory Ecology and its contribution to Quality of Life, with Emphasis on the Individual]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Since 2010 the hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to
sponsor a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the
hearing aid industry, its customers, and end users. The framework for this
collaboration is the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC)</a>.</p>
<p>The focus of this RFP is Auditory Ecology, a concept introduced by Gatehouse
(1999) to describe the relationship between the acoustic environments
experienced in everyday life and the perceptual demands of different
individuals in these environments.  Gatehouse found that individuals with more
diverse auditory lifestyles had a stronger preference for more sophisticated
signal processing strategies. Research that seeks to develop tools for
characterizing auditory lifestyles and relates these to the effects of signal
processing would be of benefit to the hearing-aid industry.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing IRC web site</a>. The
deadline for proposals is August 21, 2016, and decisions will be announced by December 31,
2016.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2016-auditory-ecology</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2016-auditory-ecology</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2015 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>By the deadline of August 2015 IRC had received 6 outstanding grant proposals
from leading universities around the world in response to the most recent RFP,
which focuses on Big Data Outcome Measurement and Treatment.</p>
<p>IRC is very pleased to announce that the 2015 Grant recipients are the teams
lead by Principal Investigators Dr Peter Nordquist, Research Institute
Hörselbron, KTH Stockholm, Sweden as well as the team lead by Dr Harvey Dillon,
National Acoustic Laboratories, Sydney, Australia. Each team received an award
of 150’000 USD to pursue their research.</p>
<p>Both projects look at how coordinated data collection in audiological service
delivery systems can be exploited to examine relations between patient
characteristics, treatment outcomes, and process variables. This may provide
new evidence for the development of improved treatment. Meanwhile, the
diversity of real-life clinical practice may cause any data to be very ‘noisy’,
potentially invalidating conclusions regarding cause and effect.</p>
<p>“Once again we are very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from universities all around the world. We know it takes a big effort to
prepare such applications, and we want to express our thankfulness to all
applicants for their contribution,” said Stefan Launer, 2016-2017 Chair of the
IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2015-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2015-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2015 RFP: Outcome Measurement and Treatment Prescription]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Since 2010 the hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to
sponsor a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the
hearing aid industry, its customers, and end users. The framework for this
collaboration is the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC)</a>.</p>
<p>Coordinated data collection in audiological service delivery systems can be
exploited to examine relations between patient characteristics, treatment
outcomes, and process variables. This may provide new evidence for the
development of improved treatment. Meanwhile, the diversity of real-life
clinical practice may cause any data to be very ‘noisy’, potentially
invalidating conclusions regarding cause and effect. IRC wishes to promote
serious research in this area, and therefore this year the IRC is requesting
proposals within the topic of ‘Large-scale approaches to outcome measurement
and treatment prescription’. The $300,000 funding pool is open to research labs
around the world.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing IRC web site</a>. The
deadline for proposals is August 16, 2015, and decisions will be announced by
December 31, 2015.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2015-outcome-measurement-and-treatment-prescription</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2015-outcome-measurement-and-treatment-prescription</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2014 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>By the deadline in August 2014 IRC had received 21 outstanding grant proposals
from leading universities around the world in response to the most recent RFP.
While last year’s grant recipients, Steven Colburn (Boston University, USA) &amp;
Theo Goverts (VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam) and Gitte Keidser &amp;
Virginia Best (National Acoustic Laboratories, Australia) were focussing on
research in the field of Perception of dynamic spatial listening scenarios, the
2014 RFP focuses on Neurodegeneration: Perceptual Consequences and
Quantification in Human Subjects.</p>
<p>IRC is very pleased to announce that the 2014 Grant recipients are Prof. John
Grose, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and Dr. Elizabeth Beach,
PhD, National Acoustic Laboratories, Australia.</p>
<p>John Grose is Professor at the department of Otolaryngology - Head &amp; Neck
Surgery, and his work will focus on characterizing auditory neurodegeneration
in humans, combining basic psychoacoustic measurements with
electrophysiological measurements.</p>
<p>“There is increasing evidence that noise exposure can result in permanent
hearing changes even if the ability to detect quiet sounds remains intact”, Dr
John Grose says - “This project looks specifically at whether regular
attendance at loud music venues is associated with a compromised ability to
discern audible sounds over the long term. I am very enthusiastic be working
with the IRC on this project, as we consider this study an important next step
in our understanding of the perceptual consequences of hearing loss and aging”.</p>
<p>The project will be undertaken in the Hearing Research Laboratory at the
University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, which has a distinguished history
of studying human auditory function using both behavioral and
electrophysiological tests.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Beach is a Research Psychologist at NAL, and her work will focus at
addressing outcomes of a potential target group of noise exposed workers, in
combination with basic auditory assessments. Elizabeth says: “It was such a
great topic for the IRC to initiate a request on, and it was a topic that we
had already been thinking about a lot. We&#39;re very much looking forward to the
study and reaching a better understanding of the nature of hidden hearing
loss.&quot;</p>
<p>Both projects look at the so-called ‘hidden hearing loss’ being an implication
of degeneration of neurons in the auditory fibers, due to noise exposure. The
term ‘hidden hearing loss’ refers to the fact that it is not obvious from an
audiogram, that hearing has deteriorated (significantly), but speech
understanding in noise is severely reduced.</p>
<p>“Once again we are very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from universities all around the world. We know it takes a big effort to
prepare such applications, and we want to express our thankfulness to all
applicant for their contribution,” said Joel Beilin, 2014-2015 Chair of the
IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2014-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2014-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2014 RFP: Neurodegeneration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>During the last five years, our understanding of the pathophysiology of hearing
loss has been substantially enhanced, and challenged, by the discovery of
auditory neuronal damage, which does not always manifest in the audiogram. This
is a very interesting new area of research, and this year the IRC is requesting
proposals within the topic of Neurodegeneration: Perceptual Consequences and
Quantification in Human Subjects. The $300,000 grant is open to research labs
around the world.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">IRC website</a>. The
deadline for proposals is August 15, 2014, and decisions will be announced by
December 31, 2014.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2014-neurodegeneration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2014-neurodegeneration</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2013 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The IRC received 24 outstanding grant proposals from around the world for this
most recent RFP. <a href="/news/announcing-the-first-irc-grant-recipients/">Last May</a>,
Piers Dawes, Ph.D., and Andrea Pittman, Ph.D., were
awarded the first IRC grants for research aimed to advance the understanding of
the interaction between cognition and hearing aids.</p>
<p>Goverts is head of the Audiological Center and a medical physicist audiologist
at the VU University Medical Center in Amsterdam, and Colburn is the director
of the Hearing Research Center and professor of biomedical engineering at
Boston University. Their research will take a detailed look at speech
recognition in realistic dynamic listening scenarios.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited by the opportunities provided by this grant to address
questions related to spatial hearing in complicated listening situations,” said
Goverts. “We hope that our work will help audiologists to better treat people
with hearing problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Best currently works as a research scientist with the National Acoustic
Laboratories in Sydney, Australia, and as a research assistant professor at
Hearing Research Center, Boston University. Her research will examine a dynamic
speech comprehension task for assessing real-world listening ability and
hearing aid benefit.</p>
<p>“We are delighted that the IRC has decided to support this work. The grant will
enable us to develop a new test that measures how well people can follow
dynamic conversations in noisy places,” said Best. “Using this test we will
also gather new knowledge about how hearing loss and hearing aids affect this
critical part of everyday communication.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are very pleased to have received quite a large number of excellent
proposals from renowned universities all around the world, and we want to thank
every applicant for his or her contribution,” said Stefan Launer, 2013 Chair of
the IRC. “It shows us that we have selected a topic of great interest and
potential for the research community and thus our entire industry. We have
selected proposals that present a mixture between innovative approaches to
basic science and direct clinical applicability. We wish the two selected
research teams great success with their projects, and we very much look forward
to seeing the results being openly and publicly presented and discussed.
Hopefully this initiative will stimulate further research in this exciting
field.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2013-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2013-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 14:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RFP 2013 Perception of dynamic spatial listening scenarios]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dear colleagues,</p>
<p>The hearing aid industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to create
the Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) to develop and direct a
non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the hearing
aid industry, its customers, and end users.</p>
<p>The IRC is requesting proposals for a research project on “Perception of
dynamic spatial listening scenarios”. The $300,000 grant pool is open to
research labs around the world.  Further details are available on the IRC web
site at www.hearingirc.com and in attached document.</p>
<p>The IRC board is comprised of the heads of research from the top hearing aid
manufacturers in the world including GN ReSound’s Andrew Dittberner; Oticon’s
Graham Naylor; Phonak’s Stefan Launer; Siemens’ Joel Beilin; Starkey Hearing
Technologies’ Brent Edwards; and Widex’ Lars Sunesen.</p>
<p>The deadline for proposals is September 1, 2013, and decisions will be
announced by December 31, 2013.</p>
<p>I am chairman of IRC for 2013, and enquiries may be directed to me or any of
the others named above.</p>
<p>Please feel free to further distribute this email to researcher you think might
are interested in this field.</p>
<p>Best regards<br>
Stefan Launer</p>
<p>VP Science and Technology<br>
Phonak AG</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2013-perception-of-dynamic-spatial-listening-scenarios</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2013-perception-of-dynamic-spatial-listening-scenarios</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>