<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></description>
        <link>http://hearingirc.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:23:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://hearingirc.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:23:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2021 RFP: "Confirming The Hearing Care Practitioner (HCP) Role with Respect to Expanded Hearing-Aid-User Needs, Health &amp; Well-Being"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) announces its 2021 Request for
Proposals (RFP) for research on &quot;Confirming The Hearing Care Practitioner
(HCP) Role with Respect to Expanded Hearing-Aid-User Needs, Health &amp; Well-Being&quot;.</p>
<p>The purpose of this RFP is to stimulate research into the expanding role of the
HCP given rapidly changing technologies. <strong>Today, the HCP needs to understand
social and psychological factors, vestibular anatomy and physiology, cognitive
screening tools, and biometric functions, topics that have not been part of the
traditional scope of practice, and this RFP is designed to confirm and refine
the important role of the HCP.</strong></p>
<p>The funding pool for this RFP is 300,000 US Dollars, and the time period for
execution of projects under this RFP is 2-3 years from 1st January 2022.
Proposals for projects of two years duration are preferred. It is envisaged
that one or two project proposals will be funded.</p>
<p>Detailed descriptions of the application procedure, the guidelines for research
under this scheme, and the proposed research area can be <a href="http://rfp.hearingirc.com">downloaded</a>
and also found on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">IRC website</a>. The deadline for
submission is September 3, 2021.</p>
<p>Questions can be sent to any of the IRC members listed on the website or using
the Contact Form on the website.</p>
<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) is made up of the heads of
research from the top hearing aid manufacturers in the world, which include GN
Hearing, Oticon, Sonova, WS Audiology and Starkey Hearing Technologies. The IRC
was created to have a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda
benefiting the hearing aid industry, its customers and end users. For more
information about the Hearing Industry Research Consortium, visit
<a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a>.</p>
<p>Andrew Dittberner, 2020-2022 Chair of the IRC</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2021-expanded-customer-needs-health-wellness</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2021-expanded-customer-needs-health-wellness</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No IRC Request for Proposal in 2020]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dear all,</p>
<p>On behalf of the Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC), I would like to
let you know, that we will not post a Request for Proposals in 2020. We a
sorry about this, but reason is that the current conditions, due to the global
COVID-19 situation, has created sub-optimal work conditions for researchers to
generate the proposals. Another reason is that we, as an industry are in a
situation with careful awareness to expenses. I hope that there is an
understanding of this decision. We will return with a new a great topic for
you to consider. So, stay tuned for news in April/May 2021.</p>
<p>Thank you</p>
<p>The Hearing Industry Consortium (IRC)</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2020-status</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2020-status</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2019 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In response to the RFP 2019, “The joy of hearing: the impact of hearing loss
and hearing aids on the affective state of the listener “, the IRC received
eight great project proposal. This is comparable to previous calls on topics
that has not received much attention in the research community. It is one of
the goals of IRC to identify these under-studied domains in the field of
Audiology, and like the 2018 RFP, the 2019 is one of these and focuses more on
the psychological aspects of Audiology.</p>
<p>The IRC is now pleased to announce that for the 2019 call, we have two grant
winners. They are:</p>
<ul>
<li>University of Nottingham, Graham Naylor and his team of the proposal:
“Emotional responses in daily-life listening situations for people with a
hearing loss, and emotional adaptation after a first hearing-aid fitting”</li>
<li>University of Memphis, Jani Johnson and her team on the proposal “Does
wearing hearing aids impact the affective state of older adults with
hearing loss in daily listening”</li>
</ul>
<p>The projects both started early 2020. We look forward to seeing the results and
contributions from these projects.</p>
<p>The IRC is once again very pleased to have received excellent proposals from
globally leading researchers We sincerely appreciate the effort put into these
proposals. We are pleased to stimulate the relevant research fields, both with
potential funding, but also in providing topics of interest to the Industry,
that consequently will lead to greater impact of the conducted research</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2019-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2019-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2019 RFP: "The joy of hearing: the impact of hearing loss and hearing aids on the affective state of the listener"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) announces its 2019 Request for
Proposals (RFP) for research on &quot;The joy of hearing: the impact of hearing loss
and hearing aids on the affective state of the listener&quot;.</p>
<p>The purpose of this RFP is to stimulate research into the positive affective
responses to sound stimuli in hearing-impaired individuals. The goal is to
deepen the understanding of the impact of hearing impairment and hearing-loss
compensation on the affective state of the listener. In particular, we are
interested in the involvement of the two reward systems mentioned above in
hearing-impaired individuals, namely, the pleasure of hearing and the
motivational aspects of hearing, and their impact on the quality of life of
hearing-aid users.</p>
<p>The funding pool for this RFP is 300,000 US Dollars, and the time period for
execution of projects under this RFP is 2-3 years from 1st January 2020.
Proposals for projects of two years duration are preferred. It is envisaged
that one or two project proposals will be funded.</p>
<p>Detailed descriptions of the application procedure, the guidelines for research
under this scheme, and the proposed research area can be <a href="http://rfp.hearingirc.com">downloaded</a>
and also found on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">IRC website</a>. The deadline for
submission is August 26, 2019.</p>
<p>Questions can be sent to any of the IRC members listed on the website or using
the Contact Form on the website.</p>
<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) is made up of the heads of
research from the top hearing aid manufacturers in the world, which include GN
Hearing, Oticon, Sonova, WS Audiology and Starkey Hearing Technologies. The IRC
was created to have a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda
benefiting the hearing aid industry, its customers and end users. For more
information about the Hearing Industry Research Consortium, visit
<a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a>.</p>
<p>Morten Løve Jepsen, 2019-2020 Chair of the IRC</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2019-hearing-loss-impact-affective-state</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2019-hearing-loss-impact-affective-state</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2018 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In response to the RFP 2018, Stigma-related factors influencing the uptake of
hearing aids, the IRC received eight great project proposal. This is a
relatively small number compared to previous calls, but this may simply reflect
that the topic has had too little attention previously. It is one of the goals
of IRC to identify these under-studied domains in the field of Audiology, and
this seems to be one of them.</p>
<p>We, the IRC, are pleased to announce that the grant winner of the 2018 call is
Professor Louise Hickson and her team at the University of Queensland,
Australia. They excellently presented to proposal, entitled: ”To tell or not to
tell? The stigma experiences of adults with hearing impairment and their
families”.</p>
<p>The project started on March 1st, 2019. In her words, this research project
will provide a first-of-its-kind understanding of stigma in hearing impairment.
This understanding has the potential to inform adults with hearing impairment,
family members, hearing care professionals, referring practitioners (e.g., GPs,
ENTs, Geriatricians), and hearing device manufacturers about how to counsel
adults with hearing difficulties and their families about the pros and cons of
acknowledging hearing loss in everyday life.</p>
<p>The team is thrilled to have this opportunity to undertake this research
project. We believe it will make a valuable contribution to the field and are
excited to get started with this research in 2019!</p>
<p>A key focus of our team’s research program involves exploring the impact of
hearing loss in adults on their quality of life and how and why they take steps
to get help for their hearing difficulties. We had recently been noticing that
stigma related to hearing loss and hearing aids kept appearing in our data as a
possible barrier to help-seeking (both within interviews with people with
hearing impairment and their families, and within our video-recorded audiology
appointment interactions). These observations highlighted to us the
significance of stigma in the everyday lives of adults with hearing impairment
and their families. We were, therefore, keen to explore the notion of stigma
further in our future research.</p>
<p>A key focus of our team’s research program involves exploring the impact of
hearing loss in adults on their quality of life and how and why they take steps
to get help for their hearing difficulties. We had recently been noticing that
stigma related to hearing loss and hearing aids kept appearing in our data as a
possible barrier to help-seeking (both within interviews with people with
hearing impairment and their families, and within our video-recorded audiology
appointment interactions). These observations highlighted to us the
significance of stigma in the everyday lives of adults with hearing impairment
and their families. We were, therefore, keen to explore the notion of stigma
further in our future research.</p>
<p>The IRC is once again very pleased to have received excellent proposals from
globally leading researchers We sincerely appreciate the effort put into these
proposals. We are pleased to stimulate the relevant research fields, both with
potential funding, but also in providing topics of interest to the Industry,
that consequently will lead to greater impact of the conducted research</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2018-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2018-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2018 RFP: "Stigma-related factors influencing the uptake of hearing aids"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) announces its 2018 Request for
Proposals (RFP) for research on stigma-related factors influencing the uptake of
hearing aids.</p>
<p>While many people would benefit from hearing instruments, uptake is still low,
especially among those with milder forms of audiometric hearing loss. Among the
factors that hinder uptake of hearing aids, the stigma associated with hearing
aids is an important one. The purpose of this RFP is to stimulate research on
the stigma related to hearing loss and hearing instruments. This research should
deepen understanding of the psychological factors hindering people with hearing
impairment to seek help and especially to develop approaches to help overcome
this hurdle.</p>
<p>The funding pool for this RFP is 300,000 US Dollars, and the time period for
execution of projects under this RFP is 2-3 years from 1st January 2019.
Proposals for projects of two years duration are preferred. It is envisaged that
one or two project proposals will be funded.</p>
<p>Detailed descriptions of the application procedure, the guidelines for research
under this scheme, and the proposed research area can be downloaded
(<a href="http://rfp.hearingirc.com">http://rfp.hearingirc.com</a>) and also found on the
IRC website (<a href="http://hearingirc.com">http://hearingirc.com</a>). The deadline for
submission is August 18, 2018.</p>
<p>Questions can be sent to any of the IRC members listed on the website or using
the Contact Form on the website.</p>
<p>The Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC) is made up of the heads of
research from the top hearing aid manufacturers in the world, which include GN,
Oticon, Phonak, Sivantos, Starkey Hearing Technologies and Widex. The IRC was
created to have a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda
benefiting the hearing aid industry, its customers and end users. For more
information about the Hearing Industry Research Consortium, visit
<a href="http://www.hearingirc.com">www.hearingirc.com</a>.</p>
<p>Sridhar Kalluri, 2017-2018 Chair of the IRC</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2018-stigma-related-factors</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2018-stigma-related-factors</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2017 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The IRC received seventeen outstanding proposals from leading universities and
research institutions around the world in response to its 2017 request for
proposals on the impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in
hearing impaired adults. This topic area recognizes the importance of
considering that real-life communication does not occur solely in the auditory
domain, but instead triggers simultaneous activation of different modalities,
requiring cross-modal integration. The IRC is pleased to announce that the grant
recipients are a team lead by Principal Investigator Prof. Hans Colonius, Carl
von Ossietzky Universitat Oldenburg, Germany and another team lead by Prof. Anu
Sharma, University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado, USA.</p>
<p>Hans Colonius is a professor in the Department of Psychology and the Cluster of
Excellence “Hearing4all”, Carl von Ossietzky University Oldenburg. He and his
co-workers, Professor Christiane Thiel, Anja Gieseler, Maike Tahden, and Dr.
Stephanie Rosemann will focus on how hearing aid usage in mild-to-moderately
hearing-impaired elderly affects audiovisual integration, speech perception,
cognitive performance and neural connectivity using both psychophysical methods
and fMRI.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited about being able to follow up on our previous work and to
finally realize the project that we have been thinking about for the last
years”, said Prof. Colonius, “by investigating the causal relations between
audiovisual integration, hearing aid use and speech performance in a
longitudinal study!”</p>
<p>Anu Sharma is a Professor in the Department of Speech Language Hearing Sciences,
Institute of Cognitive Science, and Center for Neuroscience at the University of
Colorado Boulder. Her work will focus on examining changes in cross-modal
neuroplasticity and auditory visual processing in age-related hearing loss and
whether intervention with amplification restores auditory visual integration and
underlying cortical networks to a normal state.</p>
<p>Prof. Sharma said: “This is a timely and much-needed topic that was requested by
the IRC. We are excited about being able to conduct the study which will allow
us to better understand the neuroplastic changes underlying auditory visual
integration in hearing loss and how they are impacted by amplification”.</p>
<p>The IRC is once again very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from leading researchers all around the world. “We know it takes a big effort to
prepare such applications, and we want to express our sincere appreciation to
all applicants for their contribution,” said Sridhar Kalluri, 2017-2018 Chair of
the IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2017-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2017-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2017 RFP: "The impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in hearing impaired adults"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Since 2010 the hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to
sponsor a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefiting the
hearing aid industry, its customers, and end users. The framework for this
collaboration is the <a href="http://hearingirc.com/">Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC)</a>.</p>
<p>This year&#39;s <a href="http://rfp.hearingirc.com">Request for Proposal (RfP)</a> is entitled
&quot;The impact of audiovisual integration on acoustic communication in hearing
impaired adults&quot;. Hearing IRC wishes to support pre-competitive research that
advances understanding of the effects of both hearing aid processing and
individual audiovisual integration abilities on hearing aid benefit in real-life
speech communication. For many years, research on the effects of hearing-aid
use has mainly considered factors related to auditory perception. Real-life
communication, however, does not occur solely in the auditory domain, but
instead triggers simultaneous activation of different modalities, requiring
cross-modal integration.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com/">Hearing IRC web site</a>.
The deadline for proposals is August 18th, 2017, and decisions will be announced
by December 31, 2017.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2017-audiovisual-integration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2017-audiovisual-integration</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2016 Grant Recipients]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>By the deadline of August 2016 IRC had received a large number of outstanding
grant proposals from leading universities around the world in response to this
year’s request for proposals on auditory ecology and its contribution to quality
of life, with emphasis on the individual.</p>
<p>IRC is very pleased to announce that the 2016 grant recipient is the team lead
by Principal Investigator Dr Inga Holube, Institute of Hearing Technology and
Audiology, Jade University of Applied Sciences in Oldenburg in cooperation with
Dr. Markus Meis from Hörzentrum Oldenburg, Germany.</p>
<p>The project explores the individual hearing aid benefit in real life by
developing tools that momentarily assess the health-related quality of life in
individual every-day listening situations. The concept uniquely combines the
analysis of the acoustical conditions, self-assessments and external
observations that allow characterizing psychologically and sociologically the
behavior of hearing-impaired persons in self-selected environments.</p>
<p>“Once again we are very pleased to have received so many excellent proposals
from universities all around the world. We know it takes a big effort to prepare
such applications, and we want to express our sincere appreciation s to all
applicants for their contribution,” said Stefan Launer, 2016-2017 Chair of the
IRC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2016-irc-grant-recipients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/announcing-the-2016-irc-grant-recipients</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Announcing the 2016 RFP: Auditory Ecology and its contribution to Quality of Life, with Emphasis on the Individual]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Since 2010 the hearing industry’s largest manufacturers have collaborated to
sponsor a non-competitive, mutually agreed upon research agenda benefitting the
hearing aid industry, its customers, and end users. The framework for this
collaboration is the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing Industry Research Consortium (IRC)</a>.</p>
<p>The focus of this RFP is Auditory Ecology, a concept introduced by Gatehouse
(1999) to describe the relationship between the acoustic environments
experienced in everyday life and the perceptual demands of different
individuals in these environments.  Gatehouse found that individuals with more
diverse auditory lifestyles had a stronger preference for more sophisticated
signal processing strategies. Research that seeks to develop tools for
characterizing auditory lifestyles and relates these to the effects of signal
processing would be of benefit to the hearing-aid industry.</p>
<p>Applications are available on the <a href="http://hearingirc.com">Hearing IRC web site</a>. The
deadline for proposals is August 21, 2016, and decisions will be announced by December 31,
2016.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2016-auditory-ecology</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hearingirc.com/news/rfp-2016-auditory-ecology</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>